A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1957
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1957
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.635-I
This collection consists of 10,200 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 12 July 1963.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
There are also architectural drawings of the Student Activities Building Landscape Site Plans and the Clinch Valley College of the University of Virginia Site Plan.
Contents List
- General Files, 1957
  - "A - Am" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 1)
  - "An - Az" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 1)
  - Admissions 1957 (Box 1)
  - Air Force 1957 (Box 1)
  - Airport 1957 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association 1957 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund 1957 (Box 1)
  - American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities 1957 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors 1957 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education 1957 (Box 2)
  - American Field Service 1957 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "A" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "B" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "C" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "D" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "E" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "F" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "G" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "H" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "I" (folder empty) 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "J" (folder empty) 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "K" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "L" (folder empty) 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "M" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "N" (folder empty) 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "O" (folder empty) 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "P" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "Q" (folder empty) 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "R" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "S" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "T" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "U" (folder empty) 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "V" (folder empty) 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "W" 1957 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "X - Y - Z" (folder empty) 1957 (Box 2)
  - Architecture 1957 (Box 2)
  - Army - General 1957 (Box 2)
  - Army - ROTC 1957 (Box 2)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's (J.A.G.) Office 1957 (Box 2)
  - Art 1957 (Box 2)
  - Art Commission 1957 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Colleges 1957 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Universities 1957 (Box 3)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1957 (Box 3)
  - Astronomy 1957 (Box 3)
  - Athletics 1957 (Box 3)
  - Athletics - Commonwealth Day 1957 (Box 3)
  - Athletics - NCAA 1957 (Box 3)
  - Attorney General (folder empty) 1957 (Box 3)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts (folder empty) 1957 (Box 3)
  - "Ba -Bl" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 4)
  - "Bm - Bz" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 4)
  - Bibliographic Society 1957 (Box 4)
  - Biology 1957 (Box 4)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1957 (Box 4)
  - Blandy Farm 1957 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - General 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Architects and Engineers 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Atomic Reactor 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Clinch Valley College, January - June 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Clinch Valley College, July - December 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Children's Rehabilitation Center 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Contracts (folder empty) 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Engineering Building 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - J.A.G. Dormitory 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Law School 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Life Science Building (folder empty) 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Medical Buildings 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Naval Armory (folder empty) 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Northern Virginia College 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Piedmont 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Power Plant and Heating Main 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Reactor 1957 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Student Activities Building 1957 (Box 6)
  - Bureau Population and Economic Research 1957 (Box 6)
  - Bureau of Public Administration 1957 (Box 6)
  - Bursar 1957 (Box 6)
  - Business Administration, Graduate School of: January - June 1957 (Box 6)
  - Business Administration, Graduate School of: July - December 1957 (Box 6)
  - Byrd, Harry F., Jr. 1957 (Box 6)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 7)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 7)
  - Carnegie Foundation 1957 (Box 7)
  - Catalogues 1957 (Box 7)
  - Cavalier Daily 1957 (Box 7)
  - Chemistry 1957 (Box 7)
  - Chemistry - John Lee Pratt Trace Analysis Laboratory 1957 (Box 7)
  - Civilian Defense 1957 (Box 7)
  - Classics 1957 (Box 7)
  - Clippings 1957 (Box 7)
  - College of Arts and Sciences: January - June 1957 (Box 7)
  - College of Arts and Sciences: July - December 1957 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Accounts (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Advanced Standing for Exceptional Students (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Administrative Policy of the Hospital (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - All-University Advisory (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Arboretum (O. E. White) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Art Museum 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Athletic (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Atlantic Union (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Balch Estate (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Biology Advisory 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Blandy Farm 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Board 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Business Administration, Graduate School of (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Calendar 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Catalogue (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Cemetery (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Chapel 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Clinch Valley College Building (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - College, Capacity of (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - College Costs 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - College and Education 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Reorganization (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Commerce, McIntire Undergraduate School of (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Commerce, College and Business Administration 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Commerce, McIntire Undergraduate School 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Contractual Relations (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Doshisa University Exchange Program 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Education Advisory 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Educational Program for Special Training of Handicapped Children (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Emeritus Professors 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Engineering and Applied Science Development Program, U.Va., V.M.I., and V.P.I. 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Engineering Experiment Station Advisory 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Extension (folder empty) 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Extension Division, Head of 1957 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Faculty Health Plan (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fellowship Awards (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fire Protection (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Food Service and Housing (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Foreign Affairs Advisory (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fraternity 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fraternity Investigation 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fulbright Fellowship Award 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Graduate 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Hospital Architectural Advisory (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Lectures - Page-Barbour and J. W. Richard (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Lectures, Special (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Library (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Life Science Building Plan 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - McConnell Award 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Mary Washington College 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Medical Board of the Hospital (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Mountain Lake Biological Station (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Nursing School Advisory (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Nursing Work Study (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Patents 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Planning 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Power Plant (folder empty) 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - President's Council 1957 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Richmond Area University Center Research Council 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Rushton Seminar 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Schedule and Classroom Assignments (folder empty) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Scholarships, Loans and Employment (folder empty) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Science Education (folder empty) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Science Reorganization 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Snavely (Miscellaneous matters) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Student Activities Building (decorating and furnishing) (folder empty) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Student Union 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Student Activities (folder empty) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Student Health 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Summer Session (folder empty) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Summer Session, Graduate Degrees (folder empty) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Traffic Control (folder empty) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Tree 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Undergraduates, University 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Virginia Quarterly Review(folder empty) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Virginia Status of University Students (folder empty) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Commons (see Food Services) (folder empty) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1957 (Box 10)
  - Council of State Governments (folder empty) 1957 (Box 10)
  - Comptroller 1957 (Box 10)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 11)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 11)
  - Economics 1957 (Box 11)
  - Education 1957 (Box 11)
  - Endowment fund - Alumni Board of Trustees 1957 (Box 11)
  - Endowment - Alumni Board of Trustees Endowment 1957 (Box 11)
  - Endowment - Alumni Endowment Funds (general fund) (Centennial Fund) 1957 (Box 11)
  - Endowment - Alumni Board of Trustees Stationary 1957 (Box 11)
  - Engineering 1957 (Box 12)
  - English 1957 (Box 12)
  - Enrollment 1957 (Box 12)
  - Extension - January - June 1957 (Box 12)
  - Extension - July - December 1957 (Box 12)
  - Extension - Southwest Virginia 1957 (Box 12)
  - Extension - Northern Virginia 1957 (Box 12)
  - Extension - Richmond 1957 (Box 12)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 13)
  - Faculty 1957 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1957 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Ford Foundation 1957 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright 1957 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1957 (Box 13)
  - Finals 1957 (Box 13)
  - Food Services 1957 (Box 13)
  - Foreign Affairs 1957 (Box 13)
  - Forestry 1957 (Box 13)
  - Forms (folder empty) 1957 (Box 13)
  - Founder's Day 1957 (Box 13)
  - Fraternities 1957 (Box 13)
  - Fund for Adult Education 1957 (Box 13)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 14)
  - General Education Board (folder empty) 1957 (Box 14)
  - Geography (folder empty) 1957 (Box 14)
  - Geology 1957 (Box 14)
  - Germanic Languages and Russian (folder empty) 1957 (Box 14)
  - Gifts and Grants 1957 (Box 14)
  - Governor's Office 1957 (Box 14)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1957 (Box 14)
  - "Ha - Hk" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 14)
  - "Hm - Hz" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 14)
  - Highway Department 1957 (Box 14)
  - Hildreth, W. S. 1957 (Box 14)
  - History 1957 (Box 15)
  - History - Madison 1957 (Box 15)
  - Honor System 1957 (Box 15)
  - Hospital - January - June 1957 (Box 15)
  - Hospital - July - December 1957 (Box 15)
  - Hospital - Statistical Reports 1957 (Box 15)
  - Housing 1957 (Box 15)
  - Hull, Cordell, Foundation 1957 (Box 15)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 16)
  - International Association of Universities (folder empty) 1957 (Box 16)
  - Institute for International Education 1957 (Box 16)
  - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1957 (Box 16)
  - Insurance 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "A" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "B" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "C" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "D" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "E" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "F" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "G" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "H" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "I" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "J" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "K" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "L" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "M" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "N" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "O" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "P" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "Q" (folder empty) 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "R" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "S" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "T" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "U" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "V" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "W" 1957 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "X - Y - Z" 1957 (Box 16)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 18)
  - Jamestown Festival 1957 (Box 18)
  - Japan Christian University 1957 (Box 18)
  - Jefferson, Thomas - Memorial Foundation 1957 (Box 18)
  - Jefferson, Thomas - Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 18)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 18)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 18)
  - Law School 1957 (Box 18)
  - Lectures - General 1957 (Box 18)
  - Lectures - Page-Barbour 1957 (Box 18)
  - Richard 1957 (Box 18)
  - Legal Matters 1957 (Box 18)
  - Legislative Program 1957 (Box 18)
  - Library 1957 (Box 18)
  - "Ma - Me" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 19)
  - "Mi - Mz" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 19)
  - Madison Hall 1957 (Box 19)
  - McConnell Award 1957 (Box 19)
  - Mary Washington College - Dean Alvey 1957 (Box 19)
  - Mary Washington College - Dr. Simpson, Chancellor 1957 (Box 19)
  - Mary Washington College - Mr. Woodward 1957 (Box 19)
  - Mary Washington College - Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 19)
  - Mathematics 1957 (Box 19)
  - Medicine 1957 (Box 19)
  - Music 1957 (Box 19)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 20)
  - National Association of State Universities 1957 (Box 20)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1957 (Box 20)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews 1957 (Box 20)
  - National Education Association 1957 (Box 20)
  - National Science Foundation 1957 (Box 20)
  - Navy - General 1957 (Box 20)
  - Navy - ROTC 1957 (Box 20)
  - Nursing School 1957 (Box 20)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 20)
  - Oak Ridge 1957 (Box 20)
  - "Pa - Pe" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 21)
  - "Pf - Pz" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 21)
  - Personnel 1957 (Box 21)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1957 (Box 21)
  - Philosophy 1957 (Box 21)
  - Photographs 1957 (Box 21)
  - Physics 1957 (Box 21)
  - Political Science 1957 (Box 21)
  - Presidents' Council 1957 (Box 21)
  - Provost 1957 (Box 21)
  - Psychology 1957 (Box 21)
  - Public Occasions 1957 (Box 21)
  - Purchasing Office 1957 (Box 21)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 21)
  - Questionnaires 1957 (Box 21)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 22)
  - Radio 1957 (Box 22)
  - Recommendations 1957 (Box 22)
  - Regional Education 1957 (Box 22)
  - Registrar 1957 (Box 22)
  - Religion 1957 (Box 22)
  - Requisitions 1957 (Box 22)
  - Richardson Foundation 1957 (Box 22)
  - Richmond Area University Center 1957 (Box 22)
  - Romance Languages 1957 (Box 22)
  - Rural Social Economics 1957 (Box 22)
  - "Sa - Sl" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 23)
  - "Sm - Sz" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 23)
  - Segregation 1957 (Box 23)
  - Senate (University) 1957 (Box 23)
  - Sigma Xi 1957 (Box 23)
  - Sociology 1957 (Box 23)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1957 (Box 23)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1957 (Box 23)
  - Southern Association of Science and Industry 1957 (Box 23)
  - Southern University Conference (folder empty) 1957 (Box 23)
  - Speech and Drama 1957 (Box 23)
  - Speeches and Articles 1957 (Box 23)
  - State Board of Education 1957 (Box 23)
  - State Council of Higher Education 1957 (Box 23)
  - State Department of Health 1957 (Box 23)
  - State Universities Associations 1957 (Box 24)
  - Statistics 1957 (Box 24)
  - Student Aid Office 1957 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs 1957 (Box 24)
  - Student Health Department 1957 (Box 24)
  - Sullivan Award 1957 (Box 24)
  - Summer Session 1957 (Box 24)
  - Surplus Property 1957 (Box 24)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 24)
  - Travel 1957 (Box 24)
  - Treasurer of Virginia (folder empty) 1957 (Box 24)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 24)
  - United Nations 1957 (Box 24)
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare 1957 (Box 24)
  - United States Department of State 1957 (Box 24)
  - University Houses 1957 (Box 24)
  - University News Service 1957 (Box 24)
  - University Press 1957 (Box 24)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 25)
  - Veterans 1957 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1957 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council 1957 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Education Association 1957 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1957 (Box 25)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes: January - June 1957 (Box 25)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes: July - December 1957 (Box 25)
  - Visitors - Board, of 1957 (Box 25)
  - Visitors - Mr. Norborne Berkeley 1957 (Box 25)
  - Visitors - Judge A. V. Bryan 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Mr. W. Whitwell 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Dr. J. M. Emmett 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Gravatt, Mr. J. S. 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Gray, Mr. H. A., Jr. 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Greear, Mr. F. B. 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Hartfield, Mr. J. 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Howard, Mr. D. J. (folder empty) 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Jones, Mrs. B. T., Jr. (folder empty) 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - McWane, Mr. Henry 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Martin, Dr. W. B. 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Paschall, Davis Y. 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Pollock, Mr. Herbert 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Smith, Mrs. Herbert M. 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Smith, Mr. Howard W. 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Talbott, Mr. Frank 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Wheeler, Ms. Lucille 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - "Wa - Wh" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - "Wi - Wz" Miscellaneous 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Wilson, Woodrow 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Women, Dean of 1957 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - "X - Y - Z" 1957 (Box 26)